嗨 我马上就来
hey,I'll be right there.
我不着急
Take your time.
介意我喝杯水吗?
you mind if I get a drink of water?
当然不 请便
no,not at all.help yourself.
不太适合用来打发时间 对吧?
Not exactly beach reading,huh?
你看得懂吗?
Do you understand any of that stuff?
大多数都能明白 不过那本? 一点都不懂
Well,most of these I can get through,But,uh,that one?can't get past the dust jacket.
- Ted怎么没来? - 被解雇了
- where's ted? - laid off.
公司宁愿请日薪工 不用付加班费 不用提供医疗保险
Company's going with per diem workers,you know.You don't have to pay overtime,health insurance.
- 真是太糟了 - 我不在乎
- that sucks. - I don't mind.
加点班我无所谓
really,I'm not a 40-hour-a-week kind of guy.
你能签收一下吗?
if I could just get you to sign.
好的 嗯... 稍等一下 我想给你看点东西
Right.um... Hang on one second.I want to show you something.
你肯定会笑话我的 但我发誓 这个James Sidas和你长得好像
You're gonna laugh,but,uh,i swear,this guy james sidas looks exactly like you.
等等
Wait,hang on a second.
这就是你 我看过Nova杂志上 一篇关于你的介绍
This guy is you.I saw a profile nova did on you.
你是麻省理工史上最年轻的毕业生
you're,like,the youngest guy to ever graduate mit?
当时的标准比较松
Standards were lower back then.
你的智商有178 18岁前就出版了3本书和35篇论文
You got an iq of 178.published three books and 35 papers  all before the age of 18?
抱歉 我真的要走了 能签收一下吗?
Yeah,uh,sorry,i really need to get going.So if I could just get you to sign off.
好的 我们交换吧
All right.I'll trade you.
你给我签名我就签收
I'll sign if you'll sign.
- 我已经彻头彻尾变了 - 拜托了 伙计
- I'm not that guy anymore. - come on,man.
这里好多年没这么激动人心的事了
This is the most exciting thing That's happened in this place in years.
拜托 别这样
come on.don't be like that.
我可是在夸奖你
I'm paying you a compliment.
不... 不是的 我的手不听使唤
It's... It's not that,um... My hand's not working.
你没事吧?
You okay?
不
No.
- 2.32美元 - 算在Wilson医生的帐上
- $2.32. - put it on dr. wilson's tab.
我不认识Wilson医生 这儿也不允许赊账
I don't know who dr. wilson is,and we don't have tabs.
你知道我是谁吗?
Do you know who I am?
- 不知道 - 很好
- No. - good.
- 但是 先生... - 算我的 没关系
- But,sir-- I got it.It's all right.
谢了
Thanks.
不过我得说清楚 2块钱只能隔着衣服摸摸上身
Although I should make it clear That for two bucks all you get is top half,over the clothes.
感恩节有安排了吗?
Any plans for turkey day?
我会去姐姐家吃饭
Go to my sister's for dinner.
怎么这么问?
why?
就是随便聊聊 听说人们都这么做
Just making pleasant conversation.I've heard tell of folks doing such.
不如我们谈谈这个吧?
How 'bout we talk about this?
15岁的病人 持续性偏头痛和视力模糊
15-year-old.Recurring migraines and blurred vision.
好的
Great.
- 真的? - 真的
- Really? - sure.
既然养了一群人 就得找点活给他们干
There's no point in putting a band together If we're not gonna play any gigs.
等等 还是接这个吧
Hold on.take this instead.
我还以为你会反对呢
I was expecting more resistance.
那是以前的我了 现在的我不惹麻烦 不和人起争执
That was the old me.New me is static-guarded and friction-free.
你自己玩吧
Enjoy your drumstick.
准备好救死扶伤了吗?
Ready to save some lives?
32岁的快递员
32-year-old courier.
运动失调 贫血 轻微的咳嗽
Ataxia,anemia,mild cough.
CT检查没问题 毒物筛检也没发现
Ct was clear.tox screen negative.
你这么激动干什么?
What're you so excited about?
我为什么不激动? 我的手下都回来了 还有两位自由无约的职业队员
Why wouldn't I be?got all my starters back,plus a couple of first-class free agents.
我感觉就像Mike Tomlin (美国著名黑人橄榄球主教练)
I feel like mike tomlin.
没你那么像 不过你能理解我的意思的
probably not as much as you do,But you get the idea.
运动失调和贫血可能是病毒引起的 也许是西尼罗病毒?
Ataxia and anemia could be viral.maybe west nile?
没有发烧 淋巴腺也没问题
No fever,lymph glands were normal.
- 有人见过Wilson吗? - 高胆红素血症?
- Anybody seen wilson? - Hyperbilirubinemia?
别瞎掰病名了
Yeah,like that's a real thing.
- 脑膜炎 - 贫血症状不吻合
- Meningitis. - Anemia's a stretch.
558分机找James Wilson医生
page dr. james wilson   at 558.
镰状细胞贫血症吗?
what about sickle cell?
- 他是白人 - 白人也可能得这病
- Guy's white. - Whites can get it.
反正网球肘和财富已经归咱们了 就把镰状细胞贫血症让给黑兄弟得了
Come on.we get the tennis elbow and all the money.Let them have sickle cell.
TTP比较吻合症状 (血栓形成性血小板减少性紫癜)
Ttp's a better fit.
他说得对
he's right.
怎么 你觉得我永远 都不会赞同他的观点吗?
What,you thought I wouldn't agree with him?ever?
他甩了你就是因为你不同意他的意见
You didn't agree with him.that's why he dumped you.
哦 抱歉 被甩是相互的
Oh,sorry.It was mutual.
我们很好 明白了吗? 没有人生气 没有人感觉受到伤害
We're cool,okay?nobody's angry,nobody's hurt.
听起来挺炽热呐
sounds passionate.
我也觉得是TTP
Ttp makes sense to me.
- 我不觉得 如果他... - 要团结友爱
- Not to me.what if he had a history of--  One big,happy family.
那就是TTP了
Ttp it is.
做血液涂片确认 外加 血管性血友病因子裂解蛋白酶抗体测试
Confirm with a blood smear And adamts13 antibodies.
James Wilson医生 请致电分机558
dr. james wilson,please dial 558.
- 你们能治好吗? - TTP无法完全治愈
- Can you cure it? - Ttp isn't completely curable,
但可以通过适当的治疗控制病症
But the symptoms are manageable with the proper treatment.
这就开始治疗?
Is this the treatment?
不是 我们要先做个血液测试确定
No,first we need to do a blood test to confirm the diagnosis.
但他会好起来的对吧?
But he's gonna get better.
宝贝 她说过了 我会好起来的 别担心
honey,that's what she's saying.I'm gonna be okay.don't worry.
我怎么会不担心呢? 你都进医院了
How can't I worry?you're in the hospital.
我会好起来的
I'm gonna be fine.
之前你一切都好吗?
you're sure everything was fine before?
根据你的教育背景 你至少 选一份有医疗保险计划的工作吧
Given your educational background,You'd think you could at least find a job with a medical plan.
- 我们有钱 别担心 - 不是这问题 只不过...
we have money.don't worry.It's not that,it's just--
我希望确保得到了所有必须的信息
I want to make sure we have all the information we should.
- 我丈夫不会说谎的 - 没事的 宝贝
- My husband wouldn't lie. - It's okay,baby.
他这是工作需要
he's just doing his job.
他只是想确定我不嗑药不酗酒
He just wants to make sure I'm not A secret drug addict or an alcoholic.
或者隐藏了精神病史?
Or hiding a history of mental illness?
我做快递是因为我喜欢
I work as a courier because I want to.
工作很简单 不需要思考
it's easy.I don't have to think.
- 思考太难了 - 不 只是觉得不舒服
- It's too hard to think. - No,just unpleasant.
之前不管我怎么做结果都不够好 然后我遇见了Dara
no matter what I did,it really wasn't good enough.then I met dara.
她不在乎我有多聪明 或者未来可能取得的成就
She didn't care how smart I was Or what I might accomplish in the future.
我这一生第一次感到真正的快乐
it was the first time in my life   that I was really happy.
所以我决定 宁可开心也不要聪明
So I decided I would rather be happy than smart.
你没事吧?
You all right?
抱歉 我知道你很难受
Sorry.I know you're not okay.
- 我是说... - 她走了
- I mean... - She left.
回芝加哥去了
went back to chicago.
有和好的可能吗?
Any chance of reconciliation?
没
Nope.
想不想下班之后去喝一杯?
Sure you don't want to grab a drink after work?
我们可以聊聊和女医生约会的风险
Figured we could talk about the perils of dating doctors.
- 我不是在和Cameron约会 - 抱歉 我不是故意...
- I wasn't dating cameron.- I'm sorry.I didn't mean to--
我知道你是想帮我 我很感激你 但我自己能处理好
I know what you're doing and I appreciate it,But I've got it under control.
Dibala的事你也是这么说的 很显然你没处理好
that's what you said about the dibala incident.And obviously you didn't.
你这么快人快语真是帮到我了
And talking about it obviously made things so much better.
你不觉得那人有点奇怪吗?
Didn't you think there was something weird about that guy?
不觉得 实际上他看起来挺正常的
Not really.In fact,he seemed pretty normal.
我就是这意思
That's my point.
智商超高的人通常都很...不正常
Guys with iqs off the chart are usually completely...  abnormal.
说到House 你为什么回来?
Speaking of house,why'd you come back?
你的收入肯定大幅下降了
I mean,you must've taken a major pay cut.
- 人生苦短 没时间担心钱的问题 - 你太太也这么觉得吗?
- Life's too short to worry about money. - Your wife feel the same way?
她乐意削减一些的...比如说性生活
She's happy to cut back on some things... Like sex.
- 你为什么回来? - 我为什么不能回来?
- Why'd you come back? - why wouldn't i?
就像Foreman说的 没人生气
Like foreman said,nobody's angry.
没人受到伤害
nobody's hurt.
有裂红细胞
Schistocytes.
那说明是TTP了
That means ttp.
我们也是这么认为的 记得吗? 这可是好事
which is what we thought it'd be.Remember?this is a good thing.
这太简单了
this is an easy thing.
House不会选太简单的案子 也就是说他得的不是TTP
And house doesn't take cases that are easy,which means it's not ttp,
他想看看我们要花多久 才能赶上他的水平
And he wants to see how long it takes us to catch up to him.
裂红细胞说明他得的是TTP
Schistocytes suggest ttp.
很好 现在该怎么办?
Good. now what?
一般来说我们会使用血浆取出法 但病人对蛋白胶质过敏
Normally,we'd try plasmapheresis,But the patient has an albumin colloid allergy.
所以?
So?
所以我们得给他做脾切除术
So that means we have to give him a splenectomy.
对 没错
Yes,it does.
是Wilson吗?
wilson?
- 不是 - 知道他在哪吗?
- no. - do you know where he is?
反正不在这
not in here.
你真的要我们切除他的脾脏吗?
you're sure you want us to take out his spleen.
"脾切除术"是这意思? 我还以为是要给他吃冰激凌呢 糟糕
is that what a "splenectomy" is?I thought it was an ice cream treat.Yuck.
你真觉得他得了TTP? 你并不是在测试我们
So you do really think he has ttp?you're not just testing us.
对 我可没空逗你们玩
Yeah,like I have time for games.
那你究竟为什么接这个案子?
So why did you really take this case?
看不出来吗? 我在等人请我吃晚饭
Isn't it obvious?I'm fishing for a dinner invite.
吃早餐时我没看到你
Missed you at breakfast this morning.
午饭也没见到你
And lunch.
我去看牙医了
I had a dentist appointment.
知道Cuddy的姐姐住哪吗?
you know where cuddy's sister lives?
这就是为什么 我从不回你的紧急传呼
You see,this is why I don't answer your urgent pages.
因为它们从来都不紧急
Because they're not urgent pages.
我决定拿Cuddy和Lucas怎么办了
I've decided what I'm gonna do about cuddy and lucas.
- 我要拆散他们 - 当然了
- I'm going to break them up. - of course.
我的人生又有了存在意义和目标
it's given me a purpose in life,a goal,a raison d'etre.
哪怕这是一个自私邪恶且幼稚的目标
albeit a selfish,mean-spirited,childish raison.
在我看来 我这是做善事
I think of it more as benevolent.
他们的关系只有两个结果
There's only two possible outcomes for their relationship.
分手 或白头偕老
They split,or they stay together forever.
要是注定分手 来得越早对大家越好
If it's split,Then the sooner it happens the better for everyone.
要是注定白头偕老 我怎捣乱也无伤大局
If it's stay,then my meddling won't matter.
要他们扛住了 说不定感情会更牢固
In fact,if they survive it,It might even make their bond stronger.
自我中心被你掰成造福他人 真叫人叹为观止
How you manage to elevate your narcissism To beneficence is masterful.
我决定在感恩节晚餐上行动
****Indinner.
因为我是个感性的人
Just 'cause I'm sentimental.
- 晚餐在Cuddy姐姐家进行 这就-- - House 别这么做
- Dinner is at cuddy's sister's,which brings us back-- House,don't.
我暗示Cuddy邀请我 她不上当 我只能不请自来了
I fished for an invite.cuddy wasn't biting,So I'll have to crash.
我不知道Cuddy的姐姐家在哪
I have no idea where cuddy's sister lives.
请求 便给你们 (引圣经)
Ask and thou shalt receive.
别指望我会帮你干这个
You can't honestly think I would help you with this.
不是帮我 帮Cuddy 记得吗?
Not help me,help cuddy.remember?
如果你不帮忙 就逼我用非常手段了
If you don't get it,I'll be forced to use more nefarious methods.
节日快乐
Happy holidays.
情况不错
looks great.
那么说他正在好转?
So he's all better?
他可能得长期服药 体重也轻了10盎司
Probably be on some long-term meds,And he's about ten ounces lighter.
除此以外 没别的问题
Other than that,won't even know it's gone.
听到了吗 亲爱的?
Did you hear that,honey?
你很快就会好起来了
you're gonna be just fine.
我什么时候才能出院?
When can I get out of here?
一切正常的话 一周之内
Everything checks out,less than a week.
好极了 那些盒子为啥五颜六色的
good,'cause those boxes Aren't gonna deliver colors.
颜色?
Colors?
绿色...橘色...还有天花板
green...  And orange... And ceiling.
Sidas先生 你知道自己在哪吗?
Mr.sidas,do you know where you are?
咬住
Chewing.
Jimmy?
- 衬衣... - 他中风了
- Shirt... - He's stroking.
通知心脏插管室
call the cath lab now.
噢 上帝
Oh,my god.
及时恢复供血 没有造成永久性伤害
Blood flow's restored.there appears to be no permanent damage.
好消息是 这成了一个刺激好玩的病例
Good news is it turns out to be an exciting,action-packed Thrill ride of a case after all.
坏消息是 我们白白摘掉了他的脾
Bad news is we took out his spleen for nothing.
感谢上帝 他的阑尾和扁桃腺都还在
Thank god he's still got his appendix and tonsils.
那么 什么临床症状像TTP 检测结果像TTP 却不是TTP?
so what looks like ttp,acts like ttp,Tests like ttp,but isn't ttp?
中枢神经系统血管炎可以解释 共济失调 贫血 也许还有中风
Cns vasculitis explains ataxia,and anemia,maybe the stroke.
照CT时应该有所发现
Ct would've picked up something.
嗨 我叫Greg House 你妹妹Lisa的朋友
Hi,I'm greg house,a friend of your sister lisa.
可能是弥散性血管内凝血
Could be dic.
Lisa Cuddy
Lisa cuddy.
- 对不起 打错了 - 你要问吗?
- sorry.wrong number. - You gonna ask?
我敢肯定他有个完美的合理解释
I'm sure he's got a perfectly logical explanation.
不是弥散性血管内凝血 没有出血症状
Can't be dic.no hemorrhaging.
我要打遍方圆100里内的 12个Julia Cuddy
And I'm calling all 12 julia cuddys Within a 100-mile radius.
看到没? 多合理啊
See?completely reasonable.
获得性再生性贫血?
acquired pancytopenia.
- 白血球计数正常 - 嘿 Julia
- wbc's normal. - Hey,julia.
你是 呃-- 你是Lisa的姐姐 对吧?
you're,uh-- you're lisa's sister,right?
你确定? 因为你是12号了
You sure?'cause you are number 12.
可能她嫁人后改了姓
Maybe she got married and changed her name.
- Otis Campbell (电视角色) - 总不会名字都改了吧
- Otis campbell. - Probably kept her first name.
毒理学记忆法 O代表有机磷酸酯类 T是三环类 I是胰岛素类
the mnemonic for toxins.O for organophosphates,t for tricyclics,i for insulin.
我记的是"moist place" (潮湿的地方)
Or as I remember it,"moist place.
但这个place有两个l 还有个不发音的b
" That's "place" spelled with two "l"s and a silent "b.
但毒物筛检呈阴性
" Except the tox screen was negative.
只是常规性毒检-- 不能验出非常规性毒素
Standard tox screen--unstandard toxins don't show up on it.
你们俩做个非常规毒检 你们俩去搜索他家
You two do an unstandard tox screen,You two search his home.
Otis Campbell肯定藏在某个地方
Otis campbell's got to be hiding somewhere.
世上最聪明的家伙 就住在这种地方
Smartest guy in the world,and this is the best he can do.
也许他在做他喜欢的事 投快递是他儿时的梦想
maybe he's doing what he loves.Delivering boxes was a childhood dream.
苏打水 调制起司 棉花糖霜
Soda,processed cheese,Marshmallow spread.
没有一样是会腐坏的
Nothing in here is capable of going bad.
布洛芬 眼药水 止咳糖浆
Ibuprofen,eye drops,cough syrup.
要来我家吃感恩节晚餐吗?
You want to come over for thanksgiving dinner?
以前你从没邀请我 为什么现在要?
You never asked me over before.why now?
因为以前我没想过
I just never thought of it.
- 但既然我们是同事了... - 而且我老婆离开我了?
- But now that we're both on the team... - And my wife left me?
这不是个好理由?
Is that a bad reason?
是倒是 但我没事
No.but,uh,I'm okay.
无论食物还是朋友都不缺
on both the food and friends.
老鼠屎
mice.
细螺旋体病可以解释 共济失调和贫血
Leptospirosis could explain the ataxia and the anemia.
但他没有发烧
But not without a fever.
有人和你聊聊吗?
You have someone to talk to?
- 有啊 - 谁?
- Yeah. - who?
怎么 你想知道具体的名字?
What,you want names?
你失去了一个朋友 我理解 但我不是Kunter
look,you lost a friend.I get it.But I'm not kutner.
那就好 不过Kutner也从不来我家吃晚饭
Good,'cause kutner never used to come over for dinner.
我要去那边看看 所以你可以消停会了
I'm gonna pretend there's something interesting over here So you'll shut up.
原来在这里
Actually,there is.
这是原子结构图 这本全是数学论证
He's got sketches of atomic structure,this one's full of math proofs.
都很旧了 全是96年以前的
They're all old.nothing since '96.
这些不是父母强迫他做的功课
this isn't some homework assignment his parents forced on him.
里头充满了激情
This is passion.
他为什么放弃这一切?
why would he want to stop doing this?
婚姻摧毁了他的灵魂
Marriage destroyed his soul.
也许酒精才是元凶
Or maybe it was just the booze.
谢谢 医生 你人太好了
Thank you,doctor,you've been wonderful.
- 你也是 Diana 保重 - 谢谢
- As have you,diana.be well. - thank you.
你在做门诊
You're helping.
还是志愿的
Voluntarily.
他已经看六个病人了
He's done six already.
假期到了 我想你需要人帮忙
figured you might be getting backed up.The holiday season and all.
是你还是我掉到了另一个异元次空间?
So which one of us slipped through the wormhole Into an alternate dimension?
我一直很喜欢旅游 还有画画
I have always loved to travel.and paint.
幸运的七号
Lucky number seven.
House...我知道你在努力改好 但我很清楚你这么做是有目的的
House... I know you're trying to be nice,But I also know you're doing it because you have an agenda.
既火辣又聪慧
sexy and smart.
Lucas这家伙真走运
lucas is a lucky guy.
问题是 这个目的是好是坏?
The question is,is this a bad agenda or a good one?
你要么在耍我 要么是想让我知道 你真的变了
either you're trying to screw with me,Or you're trying to show me that you've really changed.
究竟是哪个? 我很想知道
So which is it?I'm dying to know.
你打算去哪吃感恩节晚餐?
What are you doing for thanksgiving dinner?
和平降临
Peace in our time.
只需付出45分钟门诊代价
It cost me 45 minutes of clinic duty.
这可有三小时车程
This is a three-hour drive.
你有没想过 这地址可能是假的?
have you considered the possibility That this is a fake address?
你认为她会把我骗到一个 空荡荡的停车场过感恩节?
You think she'd send me to a vacant lot For thanksgiving dinner?
- 如果她够聪明的话 - 她的确
- If she's smart. - She is.
所以我在车管局的登记信息里查过了 地址货真价实
That's why I ran it through motor vehicles.Good as gold.
此行不可能有好结果
This cannot end well.
我才不想要好结果
I don't want it to end well.
你该和我一块儿去
you should come as my date.
你可不想错过这一幕
You're not gonna want to miss this.
非常规毒检 和常规毒检结果一样
The unstandard tox screen was as clean as the standard one.
但我们在他家找出了伏特加
But we found vodka stashed away in his place.
为什么打领带?
What's with the ties?
让我看来平易近人 且不具威胁性
Makes me look adorably non-threatening.
派对版还是疯狂派对版?
Party or party hearty?
肾脏衰竭可以解释所有症状
Liver failure would explain all the symptoms.
派对版
Party.
这家伙是个鬼才 但背地里只喝酒?
So guy's a brainiac,and his secret drug of choice is booze?
这未免太闷蛋了
That's kind of pedestrian,don't you think?
和他聊聊就知道 这人挺闷蛋的
Talk to him.he's a pedestrian guy.
得了闷蛋的酒精中毒
with pedestrian alcoholism.
肝活检可以留到感恩节后
Liver biopsy can wait until after thanksgiving.
没错 如果活检结果如我们所料的话
Yes,assuming the biopsy's gonna tell us Exactly what we expect it to tell us,
过了新年再做也不晚
It can wait till after new year's.
或者Taub和13今天把它做了
on the other hand,taub and thirteen can do the liver biopsy today.
为什么是我们?
Why us?
论资排辈 欢迎归队
Juniority.welcome back.
- 那我们俩干什么去? - 和我一样
- What do you want us to do? - Same as me.
过个愉快的感恩节
have a happy thanksgiving.
我不是酒鬼
I'm not an alcoholic.
是啊 你家里藏着伏特加为了好玩
Yes,you just hide vodka around the house for fun.
我喝酒 但不多
I drink,just not a lot.
你什么时候开始喝酒了?
Since when do you drink at all?
我每天下班喝一杯 宝贝 仅此而已
I have one shot when I get home from work,baby,that's it.
- 为什么瞒着你妻子? - 因为没啥大不了的
- So why lie to your wife about it? - because it's not important.
说不说有什么区别?
What difference does it make?
你每天一个人喝酒还说没大不了?
That you drink every day by yourself?
一杯而已 你什么时候 看到我喝醉了?
I have one lousy drink,okay?Have you ever seen me drunk?ever?
不 但你喝的量足以伤肝
No,but you've obviously been Drinking enough to hurt your liver.
- 我的肝没事 - 不要动
- my liver is fine. - hold still.
进去了
There we go.
这检查只是浪费时间
This test is a waste of time.
["Games People Play" By James taylor]
[james taylor's games people play]
- 来点酒么? - 好的
- want some wine? - All right.
好极了
very good.
来 吃这个
here,we got this.
来点青豆?
string beans?
Julia?
不 我是帮忙看房子的
no,I'm the house sitter.
他们去夏威夷度假一周
They're in hawaii for the week.
* 噢 人们都在玩游戏 *
* oh,the games people play *
* 日以继夜地玩游戏 *
* every night and every day *
* 说话总是口不对心 *
* never meaning what they say... *
- 感恩节快乐 - 各位感恩节快乐
- Happy thanksgiving. - Happy thanksgiving,you guys.
你一定是House医生了 他们让我给你准备个火鸡三明治
You must be dr. house.I was told I should offer you a turkey sandwich.
* 说起你和我 *
* talkin' 'bout you and me *
* 还有人们玩的游戏 *
* and the games people play *
* la-la la la-la la la-la *
* oh,now la-la,la,la-la,la,la-la *
吞拿鱼沙拉 餐厅里最接近火鸡的东西
Tuna salad.closest thing they had to turkey.
谢了 但我还是希望能 赶回去和我老婆吃晚饭
Thanks.But I'm hoping I can still get out of here To catch the tail end of dinner with my wife.
- 有发现么? - 没有硬化 没有疤痕 没有感染
- anything? - No cirrhosis,no scarring,no infection.
- 血检呢? - 白蛋白偏高: 7.2
- Blood panel? - Elevated albumen: 7.2.
- 就这样? - 其它一切正常
- That's it? - Everything else is fine.
那么说我们在浪费时间
So it was a waste of time.
除非不是肝的问题致白蛋白升高 而是肾
unless it's not his liver that's elevating his albumen.It's his kidneys.
肾衰竭解释了贫血
renal failure explains the anemia.
如果血钙过多 就解释了共济失调
If he developed hyperkalemia,that would explain the ataxia.
- 至于中风... - 缺血性脑病
but the stroke... Ischemic encephalopathy.
漂亮
Nice.
但我们得留下检查他的肾了
Except now we have to stay and test his kidneys.
钥匙在门毯下
Key under the mat.
我没把钥匙放门毯下
There's no key under the mat.
哦 对了
oh,right.
你得在厨房窗户下重新放把钥匙了
You need to replace one of your kitchen windows.
我在你酒窖拿了瓶酒
i helped myself to your wine cellar.
我走时会留下一美元
I'll leave a buck on the way out.
你对她不适合
you're not right for her.
- 你就适合了? - 没那么离谱
- And you are? - Less wrong.
我开始想...
Then I started thinking...
我说什么来着?
What was I saying?
- 你说时候不早了 你该... - 她邀请我去了
- You were saying it's late,and... - She invited me.
她不知是否该这么做 她想知道 我是真的变了...
she didn't know if she should.She was trying to figure out if I really have changed or...
抑或还是原来那个混蛋
If I'm just the same old s.o.b.I've always been.
她总是给我机会
But she always gave me a chance.
832次机会
832 chances.
每一次都白费了
and I used up every one of them.
832是她的极限 你记下来
832's her limit.Make a note.
喝杯咖啡么?
How 'bout a cup of coffee?
虽然只是速溶的 不过
It's just instant,but...
我真可悲
I'm pathetic.
我配不上她
I don't deserve her.
好了 来
Okay,okay,all right.
上来
Uh,here.
倒在这儿更好
Maybe you should crash here.
这是张沙发床
It's a sofa bed.
我爱她
I love her.
病人的肝脏没事 是肾脏出了问题 House上哪去了?
***
他留了言 说他今天不来了 有啥能导致肾衰竭?
Rhabdomyolysis.
- 横纹肌溶解症 - 不对 没有水肿
- *** - No edema.
我猜你感恩节过得不错?
I trust you had a wonderful thanksgiving?
我都没印象了
I don't remember.
所以估计不赖
So I guess I did.
- 多发性骨髓瘤 - 没有骨痛
- Multiple myeloma. - No bone pain.
你一个人买醉?
You got drunk alone?
没 这是个暗示 表明我不需要跟你们谈心
No.That would be a sign that I need to talk to you about this.
- 多囊性肾病? - 没有尿路感染 也没有侧腹部痛
- Polycystic kidney disease? - no utis or flank pain.
如果引起他咳嗽的不是感冒呢?
Well,what if his cough is more than just a cold?
他没咳嗽
He hasn't been coughing.
他病史里有 而且他药柜里有止咳糖浆
It's in his history,and we found A new bottle of cough syrup in his medicine cabinet.
咳嗽可能是肺出血肾炎综合症 影响肾脏和肺部
Cough could mean goodpasture syndrome.Affects kidneys and lungs.
给他用免疫抑制剂和透析
Start him on immunosuppressors and dialysis.
先跟House说一声 然后我们再做
We'll do it after we run it by house.
他不回传呼 我们应该可以做主
he's not answering his pager.Looks like he's leaving it up to us.
是我们做主 不是你一个人
Us,not you.
既然没有不同意见 你俩就改日再争吧
and since we don't disagree,You can save your fight for another case.
我得吊着这玩意多久?
How long do I have to be hooked up for?
每天4到6个小时 直到你情况改善
Four to six hours a day until we see an improvement.
- 要是没改善呢? - 那就吊着 直到找着器官移植为止
- What if you don't? - Then we keep doing it until he gets a transplant.
之前你们很确定是脾脏的问题 后来又说是肝脏
you were sure it was his spleen,And then you were sure it was his liver,
当时他还反驳过 现在你们又确定是肾脏出问题了
which he told you it wasn't,and now you're sure it's his kidneys.
肯定是肾脏问题没错
it's definitely his kidneys.
只是还不知病因是什么
We just don't know why it's his kidneys.
有跟Cameron联系过么?
Any word from cameron?
没
Nope.
我做完诊断 会去见个辅导师
I started seeing a counselor after my diagnosis.
她挺不错的
She's really good.
为啥大家都觉得天下所有人一样呢?
Why does everyone assume that everyone works In the exact same way?
本来就差不多啊
We pretty much do.
我们以为人人都不相同 像雪花那样 但这只是自负作祟
Our egos want us to think we're all snowflakes,No two alike,
但实质上我们想要的都一样
but really we all want the same things.
爱情 宽恕 巧克力之类
Love,forgiveness... Chocolate.
我只想要一个人待着 我得怎么做才能清静一下?
Well,what I want is for everyone to leave me alone.how do I get that?
你昨晚跟Lucas说了什么?
What did you say to lucas last night?
只记得辅音说了不少
I know there were a lot of consonants.
我都不记得自己是咋过来的 更别提说了些啥了
I don't remember how I got here,never mind what I said.
我刚跟他聊过 他说我们最好不要再见面了
well,i just talked to him.And he said he thought it'd be better If we stopped seeing each other.
他说他没意识到 我跟你之间还有那么多未了之情
Said he didn't realize How much there still was between you and me,
他不想破坏我们可能的未来
And he didn't want to get caught in the middle of us.
我当时醉了
I was drunk.
- 不管我说了啥 他都不该... - 我真的受够了 House
- Whatever I said,he can't really--  I've had enough,house.
骗了你之后 我还真觉得内疚
I actually felt bad about scamming you.
可你不仅辜负了我的期望 而且还得寸进尺
But then you lived down to my expectations and then some.
从没有"我们"这回事
There is no "us.
将来也永远不会有
" There never will be.
奏效啦
It worked.
求你告诉我 你说的是某医疗手段
Please tell me you're talking about a medical procedure.
他们今天早上分手啦
They split up this morning.
我头一个告诉的就是你
You're the very first one I've told.
你觉得她接下来就会跟你约会了?
And you think she'll start dating you?
我敢肯定 她恨死你了
I'm sure she hates you.
但她的眼神是说 "网球课的钱我该咋付给你呢?"
But her eyes say,"how will I ever pay you for that tennis lesson?
真遗憾
" what a shame.
- 他们会没事的 - 我是说你
- they'll get over it. - I meant for you.
我会比他们更快没事
I'll get over it faster than they do.
真不敢相信Lucas听信了我那套...
Can't believe that lucas fell for my
"我从不敢谈及这些私事 除非我醉了"的爱情鬼话
"i never say this because it's so personal Except that I'm drunk" profession of love.
书上第二古老的鬼话
Second-oldest trick in the book.
你说得对 这是他的错 因为他傻
You're right.It's his fault because he's stupid.
他确实傻
He certainly is.
你真傻
You're stupid.
我是橡皮你是胶 (你骂我 你也倒霉)
Well,I'm rubber,and you're glue.
他不是没想象力 他是傻
He's not pedestrian,he's stupid.
实话说 他不该这么傻 他有右美沙芬瘾 (镇咳药物)
At least stupider than he should be.He's a dxm junkie.
右美沙芬 在止咳糖浆里的?
Dextromethorphan.as in cough syrup?
他不是因为咳嗽才喝的
He wasn't taking it for his cough.
糖浆便宜 街角小药店里就能买到 喝得太多的话 就会越来越笨
It's cheap,available at your corner drug store,And taken in high doses,it's a dumb drug.
越来越笨? 但他显然没有...
Dumb drug.well,he obviously hasn't--
跟你相比 他确实更聪明
he's smart compared to you.
跟从前的他相比 他就是个大傻瓜
He's a moron compared to what he was.
止咳糖浆成瘾会降低智商
"robotripping" lowers the iq.
也会造成大脑损伤
it also causes brain damage.
除非合理摄入酒精 大约每天喝一次吧
Unless taken with the proper amount of ethanol.About one drink per day.
他不是嗜酒成瘾 用止咳糖浆来补救
he wasn't abusing the booze  And taking the cough remedy medicinally.
而是嗜止咳糖浆成瘾 用酒来补救
He was abusing the cough meds,And taking the booze medicinally.
很好很强大
Bravo.
你为何要这么做?
Why would you do that?
你那么有天赋 为何要糟蹋掉呢?
If you had a-- A gift,why would you just throw it away?
我不是要糟蹋掉 只是不想要那么聪明
I didn't throw it away.I just turned it down a little.
我脑袋不那么灵光的时候 就不会感觉那么痛苦
When my brain was on low,Everything didn't seem so miserable anymore.
我才有勇气活下去
Life was bearable.
我以为是我给了你勇气
I thought that I did that.
你确实是
You do.
长期嗜用右美沙芬 可以解释你所有的症状
long-term abuse of dxm explains all your symptoms.
甚至解释了你的咳嗽 哦 多美妙的讽刺啊
Even--oh,sweet irony-- your cough.
彻底地洗个肠 用点活性炭
whole bowel lavage,activated charcoal.
等你体内的残留药物清除干净 你就能变成世上最郁闷的小快递员啦
we get all traces of it out of your system.You'll be the unhappiest little courier in no time.
没了它 我想我活不下去
I don't think I can live without it.
不要太惊讶 人没了啥都能活
You'd be surprised what you can live without.
让他变天才吧
Make him a genius.
真不敢相信 他看上去已经好多了
I can't believe it.he looks so much better already.
我们正在考虑给GQ打电话呢
we were thinking about calling gq.
洗肠已经清除了他体内所有的右美沙芬
Lavage has removed all traces of dxm from his body.
你又在画画啦 在画啥?
You're drawing again.what is it?
- 乱涂几笔而已 - 才不是呢
- just doodles. - no,it's not.
来嘛 Jimmy 我想知道
Come on,jimmy,i want to know.
这是个环面螺旋等离子设备
This is a toroidal helicon plasma device.
它能测量次原子微粒消耗的能量
It determines the amount of energy Expended by the subatomic particles.
我渴了 你能给我拿杯果汁么?
I'm thirsty.could you get me a juice or something?
当然了 我很开心 Jimmy
Yeah,of course.I'm so happy,jimmy.
早告诉过你们了
I told you.
你知道她的智商 跟我的差别有多大么?
Do you know what the difference between her iq and mine is?
差91分哎 亲缘关系上她跟长臂猿更相近哎
91 points.In relation,she's closer to a gibbon than she is to me.
跟她做爱简直就像兽奸
Having sex with her would be an act of bestiality.
我猜想你不是因为她 精通应用物理才娶她的吧
I assume you didn't marry her for her skill in applied physics.
她连这个词都拼不对
I just wish she could spell it.
你真觉得 跟个拼写功夫更厉害的人一起 你会更开心?
You really think you'd be happier With someone who could spell better?
不
No.
这就是问题所在
That's the problem.
我自己才是个混账 我欠她一辈子
I'm the one who's a jerk.But I owe her everything.
我很希望自己想跟她在一起
I want to want to be with her.
但我意识清醒时 我做不到
And when I'm clear,i... I can't.
- 晕厥 头昏 气短? - 有时候吧
- Fainting,dizziness,shortness of breath? - sometimes.
看病是不是都得等这么久?
Is the wait always this long?
每周只有七天是这样 腹泻? 减重?
Only on days that end in "day." Diarrhea,weight loss?
有点吧
A bit.
你都不刮胡子的咩?
Don't you ever shave?
刮 每周刮一回 你呢?
Yeah.once a week.how 'bout you?
腹痛? 有压痛?
Stomach pain,tenderness?
时不时会有点 你对所有病人都这么无礼么?
every now and then.Are you this rude to all your patients?
当然了 别以为你是例外
Oh,yes.don't think you're special.
好啦 我们有了这么多 模糊的 无法证实的症状
So we've got a lot of vague,unverifiable symptoms.
但所有体征都无比正常
Yet all the physical signs are perfectly normal.
- 你觉得我得了啥病? - 我不确定 但我觉着是...
- What do you think I have? - I'm not sure,but I think it's...
- 一份破任务 - 什么?
- A lame job. - What?
你是卧底吧 保险公司派你 来试探我们医疗水平如何
You're a rat.Insurance company sends you out To check on the quality of medical care.
- 亏你想得出 - 我说对了吧?
- that's ridiculous. - Is it really?
因为你不爱回答问题 反而对问问题更感兴趣
'cause you seem a lot more interested In asking questions than answering them.
你病历上的字显然不是个医生写的 因为我全都能读懂哎
Handwriting on your medical records is obviously Not a doctor's 'cause I can almost read it.
而且你刚出去取尿样的时候 我翻了下你的小包包
And when you went out for a urine sample,I looked in your purse.
找到个小单子 上面写着 你来门诊之前要背过的问题
Found the list of questions you were supposed to memorize Before you came to the clinic.
我本来是想找口香糖的
I was looking for gum.
- 你可真混账 - 写到你报告里呗
- You're an ass. - Put it in your report.
这样吧 要是你一会出门的时候 假装我人很好的样子 我就给你20块
I tell you what.I'll give you 20 bucks if you'll pretend that I'm not When we leave this room.
记住了 先冰敷 再热敷 再有啥问题的话 就打电话给我
Remember,first ice,then heat.If you have any problems,don't hesitate to call me.
谢谢你 House医生
Thank you,dr. house.
等等 Cuddy在哪?
Wait a second.where's cuddy?
下班了
Gone for the day.
抱歉 我不记得是否就 你一个大男人做小护士的事取笑过你
Sorry.I can't remember if I've mocked you yet For being a male nurse.
这次就是了
I think this counts.
不错
Fair enough.
我嫁的男人不是这样的
That isn't the man I married.
还是他 只是聪明了些 给他点时间吧
Yes,he is.He's just smarter.give him some time.
- 我敢肯定... - 他恨我啊
- I'm sure-- He hates me.
他的身体正在康复 他正在适应
his body is going through withdrawal.He's adjusting.
也许他从没爱过我 没真爱过我
maybe he never loved me.not really.
也许我们之间 其实什么都没有
Maybe we never really had anything at all.
来个人啊!
somebody help!
我的腿没知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
整条腿 都没感觉
Anywhere.Nothing.
我们得谈谈这事
We have to talk about this.
很晚了 我累了
It's late.I'm tired.
我知道收入会变少 但赚钱的机会总是有
I know it's a big pay cut,Bubut I'll always have the chance to make money.
我做这份工作的机会却仅此一次
i won't always have the chance to do this job.
你是这么以为的? 以为我在乎的是钱?
That's what you think?that it's about the money?
那你是不满 我没先问问你就接了这工作?
So it's that I didn't consult you  before I took the job?
那的确让人恼火 但也不是这原因
That was offensive,but it's not about that either.
那是...
so then...
起码告诉我首字母是啥吧?
Can you give me the first letter?
我们刚结婚的时候 你还是实习生 没日没夜地干苦力活
When we got married,You were an intern working 30-hour shifts doing grunt work.
但我们都熬过来了 因为我们都知道苦尽会甜来
and we both put up with it   because we knew that it was leading to something better.
你自己开诊所时 你就是老大
in your private practice,you are the boss.
啥事都由你做主 但你现在都40了 你还是在给人干苦力活
You call the shots,But now you're 40 years old,you're still doing grunt work.
你就是为这生气? 你觉得我是个懦夫?
That's what this is about?you think I'm a wuss?
他让你错过了感恩节晚餐
He made you miss thanksgiving dinner.
维生素B12缺乏? 能造成贫血 四肢麻痹
vitamin b12 deficiency?Gives us anemia,numbness.
- 不能解释中风 - 要是他有血管畸形的话...
- not a stroke.- if he has a vascular malformation--
不是大红血球性贫血
Anemia's not macrocytic.
真不好意思打扰你 濒死的病人就是这么不体贴人
Sorry to inconvenience you.dying patients can be so thoughtless.
少来
Don't.
顶嘴顶得不错啊 从王尔德学的? 继续思考 大伙
Great comeback.Is that oscar wilde?come on,people.
- 骨髓恶性生长 - 不应该形成裂细胞
- bone marrow malignancy. - Wouldn't produce schistocytes.
- 狼疮 - 哟 多谢插嘴 可惜抗核抗体是阴性
- Lupus. - Gee,thanks for coming in.ana was negative.
你呢? 再说几个白痴想法让我鄙视一下
what about you?got any predictable drivel you'd like to add?
我觉得他们说的想法够多了
I think they've given you enough already.
他们起码还在动脑 不像你干坐在那跟个路障似的
well,at least they're trying.They're not just sitting there like roadkill.
说个想法我听听!
give me something.
说个想法 不然我就打电话 给你更聪明的前妻
Give me something,or I'll get your ex-smarter half  on the phone and ask her.
House
house.
你要告他么?
You're gonna be pressing charges?
告绊倒我的那张软椅?
Against the ottoman I tripped over?
告Chase
against chase.
我很确定那软椅没有同伙
I'm pretty sure the ottoman was acting alone.
- 你这周末有空出来吃个饭么? - 起码有3个人看到他打了你
- You free for dinner this weekend? - At least three other people saw him do it.
集体发疯了呗 哪天晚上?
Mass hysteria.either night?
我不能让我的医生们互相动武
I can't have doctors punching each other out.
我的天 谁被打了?
Oh,my god,who got punched?
更重要的是 为Chase着想 我需要知道他是否能处理好自己的事
And more importantly,for chase's sake,I need to know if he's able to handle himself
否则我就必须让他接受心理咨询
or if I should be getting him some help.
Chase谁也没打啊 我被椅子绊倒的时候 他正和我一起
Chase couldn't have punched anyone.he was with me when I tripped over the ottoman.
如果你周末不想去吃饭的话 看个电影怎么样?
If you're not planning on eating this weekend,maybe a movie?
我不会和你约会的House
I'm not doing this,house.
这一点儿也不有趣
it's not fun anymore.
做好你的事吧
Just do your job.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你的脸怎么了?
What happened to your face?
电话铃响时 我正在草坪割草
I was mowing the lawn when the phone rang.
你是台电脑 我给你输入数据 你帮我分析
you're a computer.I'm gonna feed you data,And you analyze it.
什么 你还要给我输入20年的医学知识吗?
What,are you gonna feed me 20 years of medical knowledge too?
没用的
It's not gonna work.
我知道
I know.
但我没别的人可以问了
But I don't have anyone else to ask.
很孤独 是吗?
It's lonely,isn't it?
没有那么孤独
It's not that bad.
那你就没那么聪明
Then you're not that smart.
你试过自杀吗?
You ever tried to kill yourself?
- 我试过慢性自杀 - 我试过
- Not quickly. - I did.
12年前我从我8层楼的房子上跳下来 跌进满满的垃圾箱里
12 years ago I jumped off The top of my eight-story building Into a dumpster bin the day before pickup.
摔断了锁骨 腿 还有三条肋骨
i broke my collarbone,my leg,and three ribs.
我在医院的时候 他们给我用麻醉药 而事情突然间变好了
When I was in the hospital they put me on narcotics And suddenly everything was just better.
我不再觉得孤立无依
i didn't feel isolated or lonely.
在那里我遇到我的妻子 她是如此快乐
that's where I met my wife.She was so happy.
和愚蠢
And dumb.
而我虽然聪明但是痛苦…
And I was... Smart...  and miserable.
你告诉我谁是天才
you tell me who the genius is.
我爱上了她 还把脑子弄糊涂 但我知道我就想这样过一辈子
i fell in love with her buzzed out of my head,And I knew I wanted to stay that way forever.
慢用
enjoy.
如果我死的时候是个白痴 对你的良心是种安抚是吗?
Easier on your conscience if I die an idiot?
什么是良心?
What's a conscience?
你摔断的是...哪条肋骨?是左边的吗?
Which ribs...  did you break in the fall?They on the left side?
是的 下面3条
Yeah,bottom three.
那是12年前的事了
that was 12 years ago.
这很可能毁了我的婚姻 所以最好是个大发现
This probably cost me my marriage,So it better be awesome.
氧化亚铁造影剂? 会被脾脏吸收的
Ferrous oxide contrast?gets absorbed by the spleen.
除非他没有脾脏
Unless he doesn't have one.
那样的话就会被肝脏吸收 把肝烧毁
In which case it's absorbed by the liver,and fries that.
- 你在谋杀他吗? - 你觉得我给他开膛时没把脾脏清干净?
- You're killing him? - You think I opened him up and didn't take out his spleen?
所有的器官看起来都差不多? 又红又湿乎乎的
All organs do look kind of the same--red and squishy.
- 上帝啊 - 副脾
- Oh,my god. - Accessory spleens.
好吧 这是巨大的发现
Okay,that is amazing.
12年 八层楼 一个垃圾桶的故事
12 years,eight stories,and a dumpster ago,
他摔断了三条肋骨 摔破了脾脏
he broke three ribs,Damaged his spleen.
一些碎片脱落 跟着血液循环流动 到达别的地方扎根
Bits of it split off,Circulated through his bloodstream Until they landed and attached somewhere else.
所以就是ttp (血栓性血小板低下紫斑症)
So it is ttp.
我只是没有摘除他...所有的脾脏
I just didn't remove... All of his spleens.
16次脾切除术
16 splenectomies.
我肯定他会得到一套餐刀做纪念的
Pretty sure he gets a set of steak knives with that.
我能跑过你
i can outrun you.
对不起…你的鼻子 和眼睛 还有...眉骨
Sorry about the nose.and the eye.and the,uh... Eyebrow.
是我活该
Guess I deserved it.
如果我这么想 就不会来道歉
Well,if I thought that,i wouldn't be apologizing.
难道你的拳头滑到我脸上了吗?
Your fist slipped?
每个人都来烦我 问我是不是没事
Everybody kept bugging me,asking if I was okay.
你打烂我的鼻子来警告别人要保持距离
So you busted my nose to keep people off your back.
差不多
Pretty much.
- 别人会更担心你 - 可能吧
- Making people even more worried about you. - maybe.
但至少他们不会来找我谈论这件事了
But at least they're not talking to me about it.
不错
Fair enough.
好耶
Cheers.
- 谢谢你 - 不用这么感恩
- Thank you. - Don't be so grateful.
你要递送70年的箱子来还债
You'll be delivering packages for 70 years to pay for it.
谢谢你对我说的那些话
Well,uh,thanks for our talk.
好久没有过和人进行这么有启发性的对话了
it's been a while since I had a stimulating conversation.
- 那你打算怎么办? - 照旧生活
- So what're you gonna do? - Go back to my life.
哪一种生活?
Which one?
有妻子的那种
The one that has my wife in it.
你给自己下药 她会怎么想?
robotripping.How's she feel about that?
她不必知道
well,she doesn't have to know.
12年来我都是这么做的
It's worked for 12 years.
告诉你的脑子我跟它说再见了
Tell your brain I said good-bye.
好比爱因斯坦给自己动前脑叶白质切除术 你对此没意见吗?
Einstein's giving himself a lobotomy,And you're cool with that?
无知是福
Ignorance is bliss.
别动
Hold that pose.
我要印在T恤和杯子上 看看销量如何
I'll start with t-shirts and mugs,And see how it goes.
今天早下班
Home early.
他怎么了?
what happened to him?
- 你打了House? - 只是一记右勾拳
- You beat up house? - Just one right hook.
为什么? 发生什么事了?
Why?what happened?
你是对的 我告诉他 我们需要定下底线 吵了起来
you were right.I told him we need to lay down some ground rules,got a little heated.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
他还好吗? 你会被炒吗? 被逮捕?
Is he okay?are you gonna be fired?arrested?
一切很好
Everything's fine.
Cuddy医生
dr. cuddy.
我们能至少当个文明人吗?
Can we at least be civil?
你鼻子怎么样了?
How's your nose?
还好
It's okay.
你小孩儿喜欢动物吗?
Does your kid like animals?
我有假期嘉年华的票 听说有一个不错的宠物乐园
I got tickets to that holiday carnival.I hear they have a nice petting zoo.
我想我已经说得很清楚了
I think I was pretty clear before.
不是跟我去
I don't mean with me.
这里 拿着 好好玩吧
Here.take 'em.enjoy.
不了 谢谢
No,thanks.
这不是假票 也不是我偷来的
They're not fake.I didn't steal them.
有个护士为攒钱让她小孩去侦探旅行 在卖票
One of the nurses was selling 'em for her kid's scout trip.
我知道不能弥补我们之间的误会 但我只想做点好事
I know it doesn't make things right between us,But I just wanted to do something nice.
我不想要
I don't want them.
- 好吧 - 明天见
- Okay. - I'll see you tomorrow.
他们没分手
They didn't split up.
她不肯接受这票
She wouldn't take the tickets.
当然了 这是"我们没分手"的风中密码
Of course.Windtalker code for "we never split up.
House 她告诉你无数次她不想跟你扯上关系
" House,she told you multiple times She wants nothing to do with you.
我又不去
I wasn't gonna be there.
她只是因我感到内疚而内疚 所以她不能拿
She just felt guilty that I felt guilty,so she couldn't take them.
也有可能是她不想满足你
Either that or she didn't want to appease you.
我没想要修复关系
These weren't reparations.
只是表现得很自责 但她一挥手就拒绝了
Just a simple gesture of remorse,And she slapped it down.
他们没分手
They didn't break up.
她只是想让我这么想然后自己退却
She just wanted me to think that so I'd back off.
我能问问你以后怎么打算吗?
Dare I ask what you're gonna do?
没打算
Nothing.
我说过他们要么分手要么白头偕老 他们没分手
I said they'd either break up or they'd stay together.They didn't break up.
而你对这没意见?
And you're okay with that?
就这样吧
It is what it is.
能这么想就好
Good for you.
House知道我骗了他
House knows I lied.
为什么? 他说什么了?
Why? what'd he say?
没什么 我能看出来
Nothing.I could just tell.
- 你想表演另一场分手吗? - 不
- You want to stage another breakup? - No.
看起来他好像放弃了
It seems like he's gonna leave us alone.
他为什么这么做?
Why would he do that?
我也不完全肯定
I'm not completely sure.
那么 我们得到他的祝福了?
So,we have his blessing?
我想是吧
I guess so.
可能House毕竟没那么坏
Maybe House isn't so bad after all.
这很好 不是吗?
That would be nice,wouldn't it?